((& ))
It is starting like this.
Let's keep looking.
They aren't good enough.
Let's take that girl.
Which one?
?
That girl. Zoey. Let's take her.
Ah... No.
..
What about that one?
?
Him?
Yes.
Our country is at war
and we are having no more school.
So we are having to be finding ways
to be keeping busy.
And what am I gonna do with this, Agu?
,
?
It's a TV. I'm selling it.
TV
This dirty thing with no screen?
?
Let's go!
!
Soap opera.
Be quick!
, !
Please, I love you.
- Please, I love you.
- I don't love you.
But why?
?
- But why?
- Because you're not handsome. Go!
!
Oh, please, I beg.
,
- Oh, please, I beg.
- Don't follow me. Go!
!
I am having the ideas.
- Go!
- And Dike is having the talent.
Dance! Dance! Dance!
!
Kung fu! Kung fu!
! !
Yeah!
!
Yes!
It's garbage.
All of you go away!
It's an imagination TV!
How can you say it's garbage?
TV!
?
It's garbage, Agu.
Don't worry, let's go.
We are living in a buffer zone.
My father is saying,
"Outside, people are suffering,
"but here we are safe."
That is why so many refugees
are coming here small-small.
Master, master,
please, will you buy this TV?
,
TV ?
How am I supposed to watch this?
?
This is imagination TV.
TV
The Nigerians are keeping the peace.
It is imagination TV.
TV
They are always buying things,
so they are easy to be selling to.
3D!
3D !
Okay. How much for this treasure?
?
Three thousand.
Huh? Three thousand. Too much!
Thousand five.
, ?
Thousand five no good.
Two thousand. Two thousand.
.. ..
- Two thousand. Two thousand.
- Two thou.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
Thousand five.
,
Some food, some food.
... ..
- Some food, some food.
- Bring out some of your food and take it.
Uche, bring the foods and come.
,
Here, take. Go!
I am a good boy from a good family.
My mother is always working hard for us.
Taste this.
Thank you.
It's good.
"B is for butterfly.
''
"Sara, small..."
"Soaring."
'...'
- "Soaring."
- "Soaring overhead."
''
Nice idea.
My father was a teacher.
Clap for him!
, !
That's good.
And another one!
!
That's good.
Agu!
!
Where do lions live?
?
In the zoo.
Shame him.
Shame!
~
Who can tell me where lions live?
?
I like my father more
now that he's not my teacher.
Since the war, he is a busy man.
He is using some of our land
so that the refugees
can be making a new village.
What we need now is medicine.
Big brother.
He is more concerned
with his muscles and his hair.
Sometimes I am adding to his soaps.
Stop that!
!
When I get a hold of you...
...
Leave me alone!
!
You have no respect!
I was trying to make it warmer for you!
!
Leave me alone!
You're lucky I don't shit on you.
I'm gonna fart on your face.
Big brother is also
concerned with sleeping.
I want to sleep
with this girl before the war gets here.
I am not liking his music.
Let me go!
I didn't do anything to deserve this!
!
I am not liking his dancing.
And how can that girl be sleeping
if he is making so much noise?
Let me go! I don't like this!
!
Treat your neighbor as your brother.
And treat the market vendor...
...
as your mother or older sister.
My mother is always saying,
"If you do not know what to be doing,
"you can always be
asking God for the answer."
..
Say Amen!
!
Amen!
Say it louder!
!
Amen!
!!
Choir, give us a song
and then we'll continue.
,
God is liking music
more than just talking.
So if you are singing and dancing,
then he will be listening to us well-well.
Cut that branch.
I'll fall.
Just hold on tight and cut it.
No way.
Then cut that one instead.
Have your lazy friend do it.
He's the driver. Cut that one.
You're too small, you'll fall!
- Shut up!
- You shut up!
-
- Go home!
- You go home!
-
Midget.
Cut it.
He wants me to fall.
If I was a taxi driver,
I'd drive around it.
Get ready!
!
What is this?
?
We've been working all day.
Give us some money for our work.
Why did you block the road?
?
We are trying to fix it.
Get out of here!
!
But we need to eat!
Take this.
I don't want your chicken.
Why are children so disrespectful?
?
Huh?
You!
!
Curse be upon you.
Curse yourself,
standing in the middle of the road.
I know you very well!
!
I know your whole family!
You're thieves!
!
You stole my land!
Me, an old woman!
!
Do you want this chicken?
?
The devil will bless you one by one!
!
Grandfather.
The lights are on, but nobody is home.
We saw that witch woman today.
She said we were thieves.
Why would she say that?
?
That woman...
...
she's confused.
God has taken her mind.
Slow down.
The land we gave to the refugees...
has been in our family
since before your grandfather.
I gave her a place, but she refused.
So she's crazy?
?
Ugh!
!
What is this?
?
Who did this to my TV?
What is this?
?
Agu! Agu!
! !
If I acted like you when I was your age,
Dad would've beaten me.
You're lucky there's a war.
It's not luck, everybody loves me.
..
Like who?
?
There she is.
She's looking at you!
!
Really?
?
Still?
She looked away.
Do you think she likes me?
?
My eyes are not good.
So you couldn't tell?
?
You don't know what's up.
When she sees these muscles,
she'll fall in love with me.
It would seem things are changing quickly
within the interim government.
As of this morning, the NRC junta
moved to abolish all political parties,
NRC
further consolidating
their control of the government
in the wake of
the recent military coup.
Lieutenant General Sangania,
commander-in-chief of the armed forces
responsible for the junta,
Sangania
stated in a recent press conference
PLF
that it was his intention
to rid the southern regions of the PLF,
Sangania
PLF
who he accused of being financed
and supported by foreign institutions.
He also condemned
the Native Defense Force militias,
(NDF)
who he said presented a threat
to the very fabric of national security.
Sangania went on to promise
that the junta would accomplish
Sangania
what the previous regime had failed to do.
Speculation on the collaboration between
the armed forces and the PLF rebels...
PLF
...
The NRC broke the agreement.
NRC
They've entered the buffer zone.
Now they want us to run away
and leave our town.
We cannot do that.
Never.
This land is ours.
Our ancestors have lived here,
taken care of it, and left it for us.
It's our duty to protect it...
and leave it for our children.
So we should send
the women and little children away...
under the protection of ECOMOD.
Where's Dike?
?
And we who call ourselves men
will stay and protect our town.
Who is going to take care of the property
we are leaving behind?
?
Dad, where's Dike?
, ?
They fled!
!
Let me go, it's my duty.
We will be crushed between
the rebels and the army! It is so bad!
! !
We've already decided
what to do with the children.
They will go with you.
He is old. We can't take him anywhere.
You aren't listening to what I'm saying.
Go to your sister in the city, I'll meet
you once everything is okay here.
I can't abandon my responsibilities.
But you are!
!
Don't think like that.
You want me to be a refugee
in my own country?
With three small children and no husband?
?
We are a family.
We should stay together.
I'm not asking you, I'm telling you.
There are bigger issues to take care of...
...
It's your turn.
Dad's sending me away.
He's sending you because
you're a little baby.
Play the game.
Turn your light off.
Now turn it on and you'll feel better.
What kind of face is that?
?
Your face is like a monkey's butt.
Come on! Come on! Come on! Hurry up!
! !
!
Hurry! I see one! Hurry!
Citizens of the republic,
living in the buffer zone.
..
Hurry!
!
The National Reformation Council
recommend non-combatants
(NRC)
to leave the buffer zone immediately...
..
This one's full. There's another here.
As military operations
begin as planned.
Wait. Help me.
Is it heavy? Give it to me.
?
Agu, take it.
Please, move. Move!
!
Move back. Go back.
No space. No space.
Please, please, I am the Section Chief.
This is my family. There must be space.
,
No space.
This one woman
and this small-small children.
- And the little boy?
- Yes, him, too.
- ?
- ,
Where are you thinking
this woman and child would be fitted?
They're gonna be
sitting in the front with you.
No, no, no, no, no.
Seventy thousand, no boy.
With the boy.
You wanting your woman to
walk through the bush to the capital?
?
I'd rather walk. I can't leave my child.
You can't walk!
!
Please, how much to fit the boy?
,
?
Seventy thousand, no boy.
7,
- Seventy thousand, no boy.
- Driver! Driver, driver!
, !
Please, please, please.
Hey, hey. With the boy!
,
No boy. No bargaining.
I can't.
Get in!
!
I'll walk! I won't leave my child!
There's no other way! Get in!
!
Give her to her mother!
Remember to pray to God everyday.
I'll see you very soon.
Always pray! Don't be afraid!
!
I will see you soon!
We'll find you, okay?
?
It's full! Everyone get back!
!
We'll find you!
Everything will be alright!
!
Take this!
You're with the men now, keep quiet.
Calm down.
Agu! Agu! Agu!
! !
Let's go.
Let's go home.
And this is how it is starting.
Go take the clothes out of the rain.
Agu, close the windows.
God, when I'm closing my eyes,
I am seeing
the rainy season in my village.
You can be finding the ground
is washing away beneath your feet.
Nothing is ever for sure...
and everything is always changing.
Agu! Agu!
! !
Hey.
Come on! Hurry!
! !
Stay here. I'll call you when it's clear.
Hey! Hey, hey!
Come on!
!
Hey!
Hurry!
!
We need to go. If they catch us...
..
Keep quiet. They'll hear us.
If we run away now,
they won't see us.
Be patient. The soldiers are outside.
If you talk, they'll find us. Keep quiet.
Agu...
...
whatever happens...
it's God testing us.
We have to be strong.
We have to go.
Open it.
Don't do it!
!
Please.
Turn around! Turn around!
!
Give me a rope!
I will kill you today.
Quiet.
Y'all shut your mouth!
!
- Y'all shut your mouth!
- Shut your fuckin' mouth!
!
Which faction do you fight for?
?
No faction.
- No faction.
- We are not fighters.
We are from this town.
We are protecting the stores.
You are Native Defense Forces, hmm?
NDF ?
- You are Native Defense Forces, hmm?
- No.
I am the Section Chief.
We are trying to stop the looters.
Bring the woman.
You are calling us looters.
- You are calling us looters.
- No. No. No, no, no.
You fuckin' shit. Quiet!
!
No, no.
Do you know these men?
?
- Do you know these men?
- Master, master, master, please. Please.
, ..
This woman, everybody knows she's crazy.
I don't know them.
Master! Master, talk to her and you know
that she's not right in the head.
!
They are not from here.
They must be rebels.
We are not rebels.
We, the armed forces of
the National Reformation Council,
(NRC)
find you all to be spies.
- No!
- Please!
!
I sentence you to
immediate and summary execution.
Waste them.
Run!
!
Please, please, please.
..
Kill them all!
!
You! Hey!
Cease fire!
!
Wanna die, fucking PLF?
PLF ?
- Wanna die, fucking PLF?
- Fucking rebel.
Tie this fucking spongebag up.
Hurry! Hurry!
! !
I'm gonna kill you, man!
!
- I'm gonna kill you, man!
- This is not the right place.
Take position.
CO Hope, take your man.
CO , .
I'm gonna kill you.
- I'm gonna kill you.
- Fucking PLF!
PLF !
Strip those PLF soldiers!
PLF
!
Strip them.
Move, move!
!
Hey, you! Keep your eyes down.
Don't look at me.
Everybody move!
Here comes the Commandant.
!
You get out of the fucking way!
What is this thing doing here?
?
Who is responsible
for bringing this thing?
?
Strika, is it you
that is bringing this thing?
?
Strika, untie him.
So all of you grown men,
it is Strika, the small boy,
that is finding this prisoner.
Where is Two-I-C?
?
Two-I-C!
!
- Two-I-C!
- !
Two-I-C!
!
Commandant, sir!
Two-I-C, what are we
to be doing with this thing?
?
This thing?
It is just a boy.
?
A boy?
A boy is nothing.
A boy is harmless?
?
Harmless, no, sir!
!
Does a boy have two eyes to see?
?
Two eyes, sir!
!
A boy has hands to strangle
and fingers to pull triggers.
Why you saying a boy is nothing? Huh?
?
A boy is very, very dangerous.
You understand me?
?
Very dangerous, you understand?
- Very dangerous, you understand?
- Yes, sir!
!
Huh?
?
- Huh?
- Yes, sir!
!
Strika, are you hungry?
?
Are you wanting to be eating this thing?
Let me see your hands.
Oh, you have hands like a baby.
What are you doing here?
?
You should be telling me.
If you are telling me,
I will be helping you.
You see, Strika is hungry.
He will eat you.
Huh?
?
What are you doing here?
The government army killed my father...
and my big brother...
...
and my father told me to run...
into the bush.
Everybody here is
calling me Commandant.
How does the Commandant look?
?
- How does the Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
!
How does the Commandant look?
?
- How does the Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
!
Ah.
.
Now, what are they calling you?
?
Agu.
.
Oh, you must say it
like you are prouder!
!
Agu.
.
One more time.
Agu.
- Agu.
- Uh-huh.
Well, Agu,
,
that is what I will be
calling you then, eh?
Leave this one under my charge.
I will be training him to be a warrior.
So you can be fighting
the army that is killing your father.
Is that what you want?
You must be saying yes!
?
!
Formation!
Say yes!
!
- Say yes!
- Yes.
"Yes, sir!"
' !'
- "Yes, sir!"
- Yes, sir!
!
"Yes, sir!"
" !"
- "Yes, sir!"
- Yes, sir!
!
"Yes, sir!"
" !"
- "Yes, sir!"
- Yes, sir!
!
- "Yes, sir!"
- Yes, sir!
- " !"
- !
One more time.
.
- One more time.
- Yes, sir!
!
One more time. Mmm-hmm.
- One more time. Mmm-hmm.
- Yes, sir!
!
Yes, sir!
- Again.
- Yes, sir!
- .
- !
Again.
.
- Again.
- Yes, sir!
- .
- !
- Again.
- Yes, sir!
- .
- !
Rambo, give this SBU some work.
!
You must carry this one.
I saved your life. I saved your life.
I saved your life. Go!
!
Straight line, straight line!
NDF!
- NDF!
- Yes, sir!
- !
Move out.
- Move out.
- Soldier, move!
!
What are you waiting for?
?
Move! Quick, quick, quick.
!
Move it! Move it! Move it! Move it!
Move! Move! Move it!
Move out!
- Move out!
Move, move, move, move.
Move, move, move.
Move it!
!
- Yes, Commandant, sir!
- Yes, sir!
- !
- Commandant, sir!
- Yes, sir!
- !
- How our Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
- ?
- !
- How our Commandant look?
- All right, sir.
- ?
- !
How the Commandant look?
- ?
- !
- How the Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
- ?
- !
- How our Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
- ?
- !
You are now under NDF control.
NDF
If you're willing to stay, then stay.
But you must be initiated.
Am I clear?
?
- Am I clear?
- Yes, sir!
!
They are not understanding me, boys.
Show them what I'm talking about.
Raise... Put up your fucking hands!
!
- Raise... Put up your fucking hands!
- Check them. Check them. Make sure...
Bring me the small boy.
This way.
CO Hope!
!
Yes, sir.
This baby boy is your responsibility now.
Train him.
Yes, sir! Come over.
!
Come over! Fucking move!
Let's move. Move. Move.
! !
Move.
Please, can I have some of the food?
You think you are soldier now, eh?
?
You's nothing.
You're not doing nothing here.
I carry ammunition all day.
You! Hey! Hey! Move!
! !
What? What I do?
?
- What? What I do?
- Wake up!
!
You go back and
stand on top of the chair.
Do it!
!
I said go and stand
on top of the chair!
!
Yeah. And salute!
Two-I-C, go and call Strika to my house.
CO Hope!
Send Strika to Commandant!
!
Strika, go.
Where you go get
this thing from?
?
Two-I-C tell me
to train this boy.
Show me position! Make sure you are clear.
Move them, now!
!
Yes, sir!
First group, move!
1 !
You stay together! You stay together!
!
Close the space.
You're too far.
Where are you looking at?
Where are you looking? Eh?
?
? ?
Look at your enemy.
Change!
!
Two-I-C is saying,
small-small we are winning this war.
And then if you are willing,
I can be finding her again.
But, only you know.
The National Reformation Council
took advantage of this instability
(NPC)
and militarily seized power
to restore UPC dominance.
UPC
We NDF refuse to recognize
this illegitimate government.
NDF
Who are we?
?
- Who are we?
- We are NDF.
NDF
I said who are we?
?
- I said who are we?
- We are NDF!
NDF !
Our very own politicians,
who steal our resources
and give them away for small-small dollar
in exchange for private pay-offs,
they are spit on the constitution!
!
They are spit on your rights!
They are trying to spit on your future!
!
I say, who is your Supreme Commandant?
?
Dada Goodblood!
Dada Goodblood !
I say, who do you fight for?
?
- I say, who do you fight for?
- Dada Goodblood!
Dada Goodblood
!
In the battlefield,
you not be thinking normally.
Do you hear me?
?
- Do you hear me?
- Yes, sir!
!
The only thing mattering
is the mission of the NDF!
NDF
!
Am I clear?
?
- Am I clear?
- Yes, sir!
!
- Soldiers, are you hearing me?
- Yes, sir!
- , ?
- !
You fight and kill anyone
who destroys the peace.
Yes, sir!
!
Offside, offside! That's what I saw.
Offside, offside! Offside!
!
Hey, stop it!
, !
All right, stop it!
!
Native Defense Forces!
How does your Commandant look?
?
- How does your Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
!
How does your Commandant look?
?
- How does your Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
!
What is it that has brought
this big family of strangers together?
?
Was it fear?
- Was it fear?
- No, sir!
!
Was it war?
?
- Was it war?
- Yes, sir!
!
We were defending ourselves.
We have to get revenge. Huh?
We have been defending ourselves
PLF
against the killings and rapings
of our own people from the PLF
and now from the NRC junta.
NRC
But it has awakened a sleeping beast.
It has awakened a giant.
It has put the weapons of this war
back in the hands of you,
the young and, therefore, the powerful.
Young men! Wealth?
!
?
We will not wait
to inherit any wealth. Huh?
We will not wait for them
to come and give it to us.
No, sir!
!
We are going to take it.
- We are going to take it.
- Yes, sir!
!
We're going to take it from them.
- We're going to take it from them.
- Yes, sir!
!
Seize it!
- Seize it!
- Yes, sir!
!
All of you that have
never been listened to before
and have seen your family killed, huh,
you now have something
that stands for you.
You now have something
that stands for you!
!
That is your defense.
That is your family's blood.
- That is your family's blood.
- Yes, sir!
!
Victory!
- Victory!
!
Victory!
- Victory!
!
We are going to seize it!
- We are going to seize it!
- Victory!
!
Victory!
- Victory!
!
You are my family.
You must die...
before you are reborn.
The spirits have blessed you...
and cleansed you.
To the enemy, you are invincible.
But there are rules we must follow...
to keep the spirits happy...
to remain pure.
Enemy never see you again!
You are fortified!
You are fortified, eh?
!
Hey!
Our enjoyment is over.
Now it is time for war.
We are warring.
We did enjoy our camp...
but from here we are moving.
Moving forward.
We are not to stay here.
Don't be leaving anything
for the enemy to be using.
We are going to burn it down.
Am I clear?
?
- Am I clear?
- Yes, sir!
!
You are dismissed.
- You are dismissed.
- Yes, sir. Thank you.
COs dismissed!
!
- COs dismissed!
- Thank you, sir.
All of you, pack your weapons.
Be ready to move.
Moving out in one hour!
!
Ah-ha!
Make sure this thing is burned.
!
- The whole place!
- Yes, sir!
!
Don't make me be
waiting for you, soldiers!
!
- Yes, sir!
Got all of it?
?
We are leaving nothing for them to find.
Burn it down!
!
All of it!
Iron Jacket.
This is Supremo.
You are loud, Supremo.
Report.
We are supplied
and moving. Over.
Make sure all the guns are clean.
Strike at your first opportunity.
They have been
buried for a long time.
Make sure they work.
Seize supplies.
Map victories.
This will keep the spirit up,
despite the UN embargo.
UN
Roger. Well copied, sir.
Our fight is a just one.
Being a freedom fighter is discipline,
obedience and loyalty.
Roger.
We remain ever loyal to Supreme HQ, sir.
Standing by for future orders. Over.
Keep moving. Keep fighting.
Over and out.
This here.
This is the route where we are now.
Listen. From here, we must go down.
And wait by that road there.
Because I think something
is coming across there.
Yes, sir.
Move. Move!
!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Agu! Agu!
!
Come. Come.
Hey!
!
Hey! Why? Where do you go?
Come over! Fuck! Fly!
?
! !
Preacher, give me the ganja.
Hey, hey.
Agu, you know,
ambush rule number one, no noise.
,
You keep quiet.
Keep very quiet.
If even a snake bite your legs,
you keep quiet.
You get hit, you keep quiet.
What is the rule number one in ambush?
?
No talking,
even if snake is biting you.
Okay.
You talk, enemies come around,
we all go die.
Right.
Psst! Psst! Enemies.
!
They are coming.
Everybody, be quiet. They are coming.
Get ready.
Go, go, go.
RPG! RPG!
!
Agu! Ammo!
Ammo!
!
Hey, you! Go!
Cut them off!
!
Where's the fucking ammo?
Fire!
Cease fire!
!
Agu! My ammo box!
You want me to die?
Search this vehicle.
Search all the vehicles.
Yes, sir!
- Yes, sir!
- I want them disarmed.
I want them disrobed.
I want this victory mapped.
Map them. Map this victory.
Controller, map them!
- ,
-
- Controller, map them!
- Yes, sir!
,
This vehicle, all the bodies,
I want them pockets searched.
All of it! Search them good-good.
!
Pack it up.
- Pack it up.
- Sir.
Ah-ha!
- !
Go and bring me my charge.
Agu!
!
Sir! I find this.
- !
- ?
- Sir! I find this.
- Why don't you open it?
- !
- ?
I find this.
Oh!
!
Uh-huh.
Yes.
Agu!
!
Where is he?
?
Agu!
!
Go shut your fucking mouth.
Yes, sir!
Agu, you are going to kill this man.
,
Please.
I'm supposed to be fixing the bridges.
You are going to kill him today.
I not be a soldier.
Please, sir.
I'm an engineering student
from the university in the capital.
I'm supposed to be
fixing the bridges,
- not be a...
- Shut up!
!
Shut your mouth.
Pass me something for this guy.
- Nah, that's too big.
- It will be cutlass.
- ,
-
Yeah, I see.
,
Does he have strength for this?
?
Yeah, he is strong. You can do it.
Preacher, put him on his ass.
,
Put him on his ass! On his ass!
!
Agu, come.
,
So when you are chopping wood,
lift up high-high. Up, high.
Uh-huh!
Then when you are ready,
you come down so well-well into the flesh.
You have chopped melon before? Melon?
?
- You have chopped melon before? Melon?
- Please, no.
,
Well, this is not a melon.
- Well, this is not a melon.
- Please, no.
I said shut your mouth, huh?
Shut your mouth.
You are making it hard.
This is hard.
It's hard,
so you must split him good.
Huh? Agu, these are the ones
that killed your father.
?
Huh?
Go on.
Shut up!
!
- Shut up!
- Please. Please.
Agu, go on.
Agu!
!
Please, no.
Chop him good-good.
Please!
!
These are the ones,
the dogs that kill your father.
Where is your mother?
?
Please...
Agu, these are the ones
that killed your father!
,
!
Chop that head!
Chop him!
!
Agu, come on!
, !
Ahh!
Strika, help your brotha.
Good.
That's right.
Watch his blood.
That is what you call justice. Hmm.
God... I have killed a man.
It is the worst sin...
but I am knowing too,
..
it is the right thing to be doing.
Tripod!
- !
-
- Tripod!
- Yes, sir.
- !
-
This will be the Commandant's car.
Take this fucker out.
He is filthy.
Two-I-C! Two-I-C!
!
Give this to my charge. Huh?
This will be the Commandant's car.
-
- This will be the Commandant's car.
- Yes, sir.
-
If you are losing it,
then I am losing you.
Hmm!
Uh-huh.
This...
- You are driving?
- Okay to move out.
Everyone, get ready to move out.
Get ready to move out, Agu.
,
You got this stuff from where?
?
From dead bodies?
Everybody is calling you "Strika." Why?
?
Are you liking war?
Hey, I'm asking you a question,
and you are not talking.
Are you having family?
?
I am thinking about my mom...
my brother...
and my little sister.
..
Are you stupid?
?
Why are you not talking?
I am asking a question.
You are not talking.
Go! Go! Fast!
! !
Go! Go, go!
!
I got you, Strika.
Where is he?
?
- Where is he?
- Keep going, keep going.
, .
Grass cutter! Grass cutter!
Grass cutter!
!
Left, left, left.
And you're having
any food that you want,
from chicken, cow,
fruit and vegetable...
,
..
Any kind of fish that you want, we got.
The fisherman is bringing it from the sea.
There's nothing you cannot have there.
And the best thing of this place,
this town of abundant resources,
is the women.
Hey, the women are too beautiful there!
Too beautiful.
Ah! The next thing you know, your soldier
will be standing to attention.
!
They are having bottoms
with specifications so nice
that the ground where they're sitting down
is also rejoicing.
And they know...
they know how to be treating a man.
How to make him feel good,
kisses and all that, huh?
Last time I was there,
my soldier was hurting.
I couldn't stand up, eh!
!
But you will see
because you are going there yourselves.
Hmm?
?
You will see with
your own eyes, gentlemen.
Mmm-hmm.
Commandant, sir!
!
Who is this?
?
- Who is this?
- Refugees from the village, sir.
They said the PLF and the NRC
took their village three days ago.
PLF NRC
They killed most of the town,
but they let these ones go.
Hmm.
Well, let us be giving
their village back, huh?
?
Yes, sir.
.
Look at that.
They are cutting people's hands.
Fucking PLF.
PLF
Radio!
!
- Radio!
- Yes, sir.
Two-I-C!
!
- Two-I-C!
- Roger, you are loud.
Report!
!
Uh, we are facing heavy fire, sir. Over.
Can you take the bridge?
?
It's very difficult, sir.
Men are fighting bravely,
but I don't know if we can
hold too much longer. Over.
Press on!
!
- Press on!
- Roger. We need support, sir.
Some of our men are injured.
The men's spirits are low.
Sir, do you copy?
?
Sir?
- Sir?
- Can you take the bridge?
?
Copy, sir. We will reapply pressure
and push for the bridge. Over.
,
Take the bridge!
!
That is your task! Mortar.
- That is your task! Mortar.
- Yes, sir!
!
Your ammo now!
- Your ammo now!
- Ammunition ready, sir!
!
Stand by!
Agu and Strika.
Yes, sir!
!
See this thing, huh?
This is a very special device.
?
We can be seeing the enemy
even when the enemy is hiding.
Come.
Wait, Strika.
Ah! There you go. See our guys.
Look, we are taking them.
,
You see?
?
Fire!
!
See that?
?
- See that?
- Yeah.
?
That is magic. Huh?
We want to take that bridge.
Now we are going to
take that bridge.
Formation!
!
- Formation!
That bridge, we are taking it!
Yes, sir.
, .
Better look me in the eyes,
motherfucker.
Who wants to fight?
Uh-huh.
?
I'm only taking the brave!
I'm not taking the scared.
I'm not taking no girls.
Are you ready to fight?
?
- Are you ready to fight?
- Yes, sir!
!
Are you ready to fight?
?
- Are you ready to fight?
- Yes, sir!
!
You want to take that bridge?
?
- You want to take that bridge?
- Yes, sir!
!
We're gonna take that fucking bridge?
?
- We're gonna take that fucking bridge?
- Yes, sir!
!
Fucking PLF!
PLF !
No retreat!
!
- No retreat!
- No surrender!
!
No retreat!
- No retreat!
- No surrender!
!
We're moving!
- No retreat!
- No surrender!
- !
We're moving!
!
No retreat!
- No retreat!
- No surrender!
- !
- Move it!
Move it! Move it!
!
Move it!
Our Father,
from dust we were created.
We shall go back to dust.
Eleven of my men. Gone.
I commit my fellow soldiers
into your hands.
May their soul rest in peace. Amen.
,
I am now knowing
the smell of the dead.
They are sweet like sugarcane
and rotten like palm wine.
And when they stay in the sun, they are
growing plump like brown mangoes.
Very true, sir.
Strika.
What?
?
You have your next mission. Stand by.
You are loud, Supremo.
Capture the central regions,
capital city, Bov.
When you accomplish that,
I will promulgate an order
making you Brigadier General.
You'll be a general before
we finally seize the capital city.
Yes, sir.
It is a challenge, sir.
But I promise you,
it's mission possible. Over.
Well, then, next time I see you,
,
I'll be speaking to a general.
And how is your Two-I-C performing? Over.
?
Two-I-C? Sorry, sir.
What do you mean "Two-I-C"?
?
I've always rated
that young man.
Well, Two-I-C is
a formidable soldier.
Over.
Teach him
the ways of a good commander.
Yes, sir.
Now, take Bov.
Keep that spirit up,
and bring us closer to victory.
Of course, Supremo. Over.
You want to be a general,
don't you, Commandant?
?
Yes, sir.
.
- Yes, sir.
- Earn it. Over and out.
Over and out.
Agu, you fought well today.
- Agu, you fought well today.
- Thank you, sir.
A-ha! What is this?
!
?
Ah!
!
Wow, wow, wow, wow, wow.
..
Agu, you are wanting to
be knowing how to be leading?
,
?
I am happy to be following you, sir.
- I am happy to be following you, sir.
- That is good,
because there is no learning
how to be leading.
Some people are born to be leaders,
others are born to be followers,
and others are just waiting to be dying.
I'm a good follower, sir.
- I'm a good follower, sir.
- Agu, you are different.
You are reminding me of
when I was a small boy.
That is how I know
you are going to be a leader.
You see, even the best leader
sometimes he must be knowing
how to be a follower.
Ah, even me.
I am following the Supreme Commandant,
even if I am not agreeing.
Huh?
?
Yes, sir.
I'm a good follower.
You are seeing this place?
?
The Commandant is saying
we must take this.
That it is important.
So, hmm, if it is important to him,
it is important to me.
Yes, sir.
Because if we get that,
then we can go to Taro.
That is where your mother is, eh?
?
- That is where your mother is, eh?
- She is in the capital.
Come, Agu.
After we've been greeted
by Dada Goodblood,
Dada Goodblood
we'll be taking the capital certainly.
Come.
This one has special juju.
Thank you, sir.
You see, I've been wanting to help you
more than the others, Agu,
but you cannot be telling the others
how I'm helping you like this.
It'll have to be our secret.
You are knowing how to keep secret?
?
- You are knowing how to keep secret?
- Yes, sir.
Well, be saying it.
- Well, be saying it.
- I can be keeping this secret, sir.
I'm not punishing you, Agu.
Mmm?
?
But I do care for you.
Aye.
..
Agu, kneel down.
Be doing this thing... for me.
They are jumping like rabbits.
Move, move to your left.
- Go, go. Keep going.
- Go. Keep going.
- Keep going.
- Move, move.
To your left side.
Agu.
Agu?
?
I don't want that I call you
and you just stand there. Agu?
?
Come here,
I'll give you some brown-brown.
It'll cure everything for you, eh.
Hey, I didn't call you to stand there.
Hmm?
My boy, what is wrong with you?
What is wrong with you?
?
Come here,
I'll give you some morale booster.
I think I'll give you
that brown-brown, so...
..
Morale booster, you know.
Come, come. Here.
Yeah, that my boy.
Yeah. Morale booster, eh?
, ?
Make you strong.
More protection.
Nobody is your friend
where we are going.
They are the enemy.
They are the farmers
that have fed the enemy.
- The farmers' wives whose breasts...
- Agu. Agu.
..
Have been feeding babies.
Agu.
That is the nature
of the land that we are going.
The collaborators and the traitors.
Our people's blood
has been flowing for years.
That's why it is time
for their blood to flow.
We will spare nobody.
We'll spare nobody,
because they are all enemy,
all of them!
!
Let us pray.
God, let us pray.
He is guiding us with
what we are about to be doing.
He is helping us.
Let us fulfill your justice.
Give us the strength!
God, we will be sacrificing our blood!
That is why we must spare nobody!
!
We will spare nobody!
Nothing will hurt us.
Because we are invincible.
We are invincible!
!
NDF! NDF!
- Who are we?
- NDF, sir!
- ?
- NDF !
- Who are we?
- NDF, sir!
- ?
- NDF !
Who are we?
- ?
- NDF !
- Who are we?
- NDF, sir!
- ?
- NDF !
NDF, spare nobody!
NDF
!
Kill them all!
Come on, move, NDF!
Move, move! Move!
NDF !
How the Commandant look?
- ?
- !
- How the Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
- ?
- !
I say, how the Commandant look?
- ?
- !
- I say, how the Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
- ?
- !
- How the Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
- ?
- !
I say, how the Commandant look?
- ?
- !
- I say, how the Commandant look?
- All right, sir!
- ?
- !
NDF! NDF!
- Who are we?
- NDF, sir!
- ?
- NDF !
- Who are we?
- NDF, sir!
- ?
- NDF !
- Who are we?
- NDF, sir!
- ?
- NDF !
- Who are we?
- NDF, sir!
- ?
- NDF !
Agu!
!
Shoot them! Shoot! Shoot! Shoot!
! !
Commandant! Sir!
!
Leave this one under my charge.
I will be training him to be a warrior.
- Yes, sir!
- !
- Again!
- Yes, sir!
- !
Yes, sir! Yes, sir!
- Yes, sir! Yes, sir!
- Again!
- !
- Yes, sir!
- Again!
- !
- Yes, sir!
- Again!
- !
Again!
- Again!
- Yes, sir!
Move, move!
Move, move, move! Move!
!
Fuck!
Fuck you! Fucker! Fucker!
!
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Out, out. Over here.
!
Fucking out! Fucking out! Out!
Fucking out! Out! Get up!
Get up, fuck! Get up! Up!
!
Ma... Ma!
... !
I'm not your mother!
!
I found you!
What the fuck going on here?
?
You know her?
I was looking for you!
!
Where do you
know this woman from? You know her?
?
I was looking for you!
!
I wanna rape her.
I wanna rape her!
You're not my mother!
!
Witch woman!
You're not my mother! You fooled me!
!
Witch woman!
God...
are you watching what we are doing?
...
?
Oh! Why? Shit!
What the fuck is that?
?
You didn't fucking boy, eh?
You didn't fucking, boy.
?
You here for die, motherfucker.
Fuck him up, eh?
Fuck you up. Fuck you up.
Commandant, sir.
This is for you, sir.
From the Supreme Commander.
What does it say?
?
Now it is your turn to eat.
Load the vehicles.
He is summoning us.
Did he state a reason?
?
Isn't it clear?
Are we going to Taro?
?
This guy!
!
You can't see my ears?
?
What is happening to this one?
A piece of RPG
is hitting his temple.
I beg you, please, don't shoot me!
Please!
Hey, keep your eyes down!
! !
- Hey, keep your eyes down!
- Oi! Oi! Oi!
! !
What do we do
with the civilians?
?
Leave one of them alive.
Send him up north to the next village
and then the next village after that.
Tell them that we are coming.
It's only the beginning.
Get on board, everybody.
!
- Tripod!
- Yes, sir.
- !
- .
Take note and act accordingly.
Strika and Agu are now part of my squad.
Mountain View. Iron Jacket. Over.
Get in there now! Move!
!
We are proceeding to Taro
with arms. Over!
!
Get in!
- Get in!
- Okay. Roger.
Echo, tango, alpha, 1800 hours.
, ,
Tripod!
!
- Tripod!
- Yes, sir!
!
Guns up!
Halt! Halt!
!
- Enemy or friend?
- Friend!
-
- Who are you?
- NDF!
-
Who is your commander?
?
I am.
What kind of welcome is this?
?
Sorry, sir. You, get in that car.
Take them to HQ.
Clear the way!
!
Clear the fuckin' way!
Right this way.
Fuck you!
!
Victory! Victory! Victory!
! ! !
Commandant, welcome.
,
- Commandant, welcome.
- Hello, Deputy.
Follow us.
Weapons are not allowed in here.
So you place them here.
Leave your weapons, boys.
Soldiers.
You wait here.
Here. Have a seat.
And you will bring us water?
Certainly.
Goodblood will see you now.
Goodblood
Him.
Have a seat here.
Goodblood says
this is a token of appreciation...
Goodblood
..
Yo! What are you doing?
!
?
I'm sorry. The Supreme Commander
is so very upset to keep you waiting.
.
Please, will you follow me?
Please sit.
What is this?
?
- What is this?
- He'll be with you shortly.
Huh? Where is the water?
?
Bring them water, quickly!
!
Commandant.
Commandant?
?
Commandant.
I trust you rested well.
I would like you to know
we also offered rations and water
to the rest of your battalion
this morning.
Thank you, Deputy.
Please, gentlemen.
Please come over.
Stand there.
Attention!
!
Commandant.
Supreme Commander, sir.
At ease, gentlemen.
At ease.
It looks like your family has grown.
They must eat while we talk,
unless you are hungry, too.
I'm not hungry. Two-I-C,
take them and go and eat.
,
Two-I-C, you stay.
Come.
Lot of food over here.
Let's eat, man!
!
I love food.
What is this?
?
You have made me wait.
You are leading me to believe
we are changing objectives.
Are we not taking the capital anymore?
?
Chief, to protect our people,
the time is now.
If we have the momentum
and we have the power, why wait?
You are not the political voice
of this movement, Commandant. I am.
Protecting our people
remains the priority.
But as you know, the world is
becoming aware of this war now.
No one will escape judgment
when it is over.
And the decisions we make
have far deeper consequences.
And what decisions have you made...
for my battalion?
?
Are you not making me general?
No, I am not.
I'm giving your battalion
to Two-I-C, Commandant.
That is why I brought you here.
And you, I will promote
to Deputy Chief of Security,
effective immediately.
I hope you accept and act accordingly.
Thank you, sir. I promise
to fulfill my duty to the fullest...
..
Two-I-C, shut your mouth!
!
Get out!
Soldiers.
You are demoting me.
This, my battalion...
that I have made with my own hands.
I'm their father!
!
Your battalion is my battalion,
Commandant,
as are hundreds of others
across this nation.
I want the ceremony of changeover
tomorrow,
so that Two-I-C can take the battalion
back out for battle.
As you know, and with thanks to you,
we have the NRC on their heels
UN
with the help and support
of the UN and ECOMOD.
NRC
It has now become
a battle for public image.
And what of my payment? Hmm?
?
What of my payment?
What share of the resources
will I be seeing?
?
Do not forget you are a soldier.
Your most important duty is obedience.
Your first duty is obedience.
.
Your second duty is obedience.
Your third duty is obedience.
Everything is obedience.
Without obedience, you have nothing.
Have you forgotten yourself?
?
I have not forgotten myself.
You are right.
I'm a soldier...
not a politician.
I will have one more night...
with my men.
Dada Goodblood.
Move out!
!
- Move out!
- Move!
Move out!
!
- Move out!
Let's go.
Tripod.
- Tripod.
- Yes, sir.
Assemble the COs and the troops
and bivouac outside of town.
I'm taking Two-I-C and the boys
to all celebrate tonight.
Yes, sir.
Where are we going?
?
You will see.
You will like it.
And if you and Strika are my bodyguards,
and I am going, then you are also going.
Are you hearing me?
?
Imagination TV.
TV
Ha! So you come!
Ha! Commandant! Commandant!
!
- Ha! Commandant! Commandant!
- Ah, Mama.
,
Welcome, welcome.
Yeah, make 'em bring
something for my soldiers.
,
- Okay.
- And my own soldier.
Hey, hey...
Bring beer. Bring soda.
Bring whatever you have.
Hey, hey! Get up!
! !
Hurry, hurry!
!
Can't you see we have guests? Hurry!
?
!
The beer is warm.
How is the beer warm?
?
No ice.
- No ice.
- No ice?
?
No light.
But I am seeing light.
?
No ice.
Oh! Well, doesn't matter
because we will drink it
whether it's hot or it's cold.
Go on. Share it.
Commandant, permission to be dismissed.
I need to be checking on the others...
..
Negative!
!
You will be staying here
so we can celebrate you.
In fact, Mama, I want you to bring
a special one for my Two-I-C,
who will soon be the Commandant.
Who is your Commandant?
?
- Who is your Commandant?
- You, sir!
!
Hmm.
But you have one special for Two-I-C.
?
No problem.
.
Hey, Mama, this one has fresh papaya.
No, no, no, no, Commandant.
Leave this one now.
If it is women you wanting,
I get plenty from backyard.
Just bring me my own.
You know my specifications.
I know! I know!
Aunty, bring us some chips.
Ah.
See this little yeah-yeah boy
born yesterday.
Don't mind him. Don't mind him.
Where are the girls?
?
- Where are the girls?
- They are coming.
We've got enough girls for the men,
but no more for the little boys.
Leave your weapons with Strika.
Oh-ho!
!
You're the controller.
How are you? How are you?
?
Look at you.
Commandant. Commandant.
You are looking very hot.
- You are looking very hot.
- Yeah, I miss you.
Oh, you miss me. Really?
- Oh, you miss me. Really?
- Mmm-hmm.
Strika.
SBU, be watching guard.
Don't be watching your Commandant
because you can't have what I'm having.
We'll start shooting.
Go stand by the waterfall.
What happened? Huh?
?
What happened?
You did this.
What happened to my man?
What happened here?
?
I was just playing with his gun
and it just went off.
I don't know what happened. I'm sorry.
- I don't know what happened. I'm sorry.
- You did this.
- Relax, relax, relax, relax!
-
- !
You did this! You did this!
!
I didn't mean to.
- You thought you were shooting me!
- No, no, no!
- ?
- !
You thought it was me?
?
- You thought it was me?
- I didn't mean to. I'm so sorry.
Were you trying to kill me
and you kill my soldier?
?
It was an accident!
No! Not me...
!
Go!
- Let's go. Let's go! Hey!
- Move!
!
Pick him up! Pick him up!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
!
Pick him up!
I want you to take all their women!
!
- Move! Move! Move! Move!
- All of them!
!
Move!
- Move!
- Let's go! Let's go! Move!
All call signs, all call signs,
anyone have eyes on Iron Jacket?
?
All call signs report visual
of Iron Jacket. Over.
Mountain View, Z Fire.
Did not copy. Over.
Mountain View, Z Fire
All call signs,
report visual on Iron Jacket.
Any knowledge on the location
or movement of Iron Jacket? Over.
Mountain View.
Mountain View
Green Snake. No visual.
Green Snake
I repeat, no visual of Iron Jacket.
Over.
Mountain View. Two-two.
Copy same. No visual on Iron Jacket.
Mountain View. Two-two
Nothing to report. Over.
Mountain View.
Black Sand.
Black Sand
Report, Iron Jacket moved out
from our checkpoint yesterday. Over.
Black Sand. Mountain View.
Black Sand.
Mountain View
Iron Jacket moved through
your sector? Over.
?
Mountain View, Black Sand, Roger.
Iron Jacket battalion moved out
with orders for battle. Over.
This...
...
This was all for nothing.
Iron Jacket,
this is Mountain View.
Mountain View
Agu, is that you?
?
- Iron Jacket, where are you?
- Yes, sir.
- Do you read me? Over.
- Come.
- Come and sit with me.
- Iron Jacket, do you copy? Over.
Iron Jacket, you are disobeying a direct...
...
Agu, these are very dangerous times.
Never know who you could be trusting.
Huh?
?
That is why it is good
to always sleep one eye open.
That is why I have you and I have Strika.
Agu, sometimes I'm feeling sorry for you.
,
Sometimes I am.
Two-I-C is dead.
God, bless the man who died
On the great battlefront
NDF
For the sake of the NDF
God, bless the man who died
Our Father, today
we lost our fellow soldier.
,
Guide him forever and ever. Amen.
Amen.
Two-I-C.
Yes, sir!
!
This was not God's work.
This was man.
Supreme Commandant was our friend.
Now he's our enemy.
But we are not fearing change,
for we are strong!
!
Strong and proud!
That is why we should be
taking our own territory...
and filling our own pockets.
Gentlemen, move out.
Let's move.
We are leaving Two-I-C
to be eaten by gogomi and worms.
We are leaving him.
And I am thinking,
"The only way not to be
fighting anymore is to be dying."
Medic!
Where's the fucking medic?
!
He's fucking dead, my man!
People are dying
just like this every day.
Every person I am knowing is dying.
And I am thinking,
"If this war is ever ending, I cannot be
going back to doing child things."
Bullet is just eating everything.
Leaves, trees, ground, person.
,,,
Eating them.
Just making person to bleed everywhere.
We are just like wild animals now
with no place to be going.
Sun,
why are you
shining on this world?
?
I am wanting to catch you in my hands,
to squeeze you until
you cannot shine no more.
That way, everything is always dark
and nobody's ever having to see
all the terrible things
that are happening here.
Preacher!
!
Sir.
Thank you, sir.
Strika.
Strika! Strika! Strika!
!
Stand up and let's go!
We are going.
!
Let's go!
Strika!
!
Stand up and let's go!
What is wrong with you?
?
What is wrong?
I am wanting to say to Strika,
"I am tired, too."
I am tired,
and so the words are not
coming out of my mouth.
Strika?
?
Do you hear that?
A song, just like my mother sang.
Strika?
?
Strika.
Strika! Strika!
!
Strika!
Someone help us.
!
Strika!
Fuck you. Life is sad.
Agu. Agu. Agu!
!
Sir?
?
Go get me some fucking bullets
to be shooting right now. Move!
Move!
!
Do you have bullet?
?
Mother.
I can only be talking to you now
because God is not listening.
Your song is making my body to move,
and I am not having to think anymore.
Not about Strika, not about this war,
not about any of the things
that are jumping into my head.
I am wanting to lie down
on the warm ground
with my eyes closed
and the smell of mud in my nose.
Commandant, sir.
We are out from bullet.
It wasn't supposed to be the way
that it has turned out to be.
Everybody betrays you eventually.
But you, I will always protect you, Agu,
because you are my son...
and a son always protects a father.
Commandant, I want to talk to you, sir.
What is all this?
?
We are leaving, sir.
Who is leaving?
?
Who and who is leaving?
Two-I-C, go back to your post.
No, sir. We are going, sir.
You are the only one
standing in front of me, stupid.
I am going, sir. No bullets.
What am I going to use to shoot my enemy?
.
We have been here for months now.
Gold miners, no gold.
No money, no food, no water.
It madness, Commandant.
People sick here and dying every day.
It madness, Commander.
Who want to stay here and die?
?
I want to go!
!
- I want to go!
- I want to going!
- !
Who want to stay here and die?
?
I want to go, sir!
!
Me, too. I want to go, sir!
Who want to stay here and die?
?
Nobody want to stay here, sir!
!
- Nobody want to stay here, sir!
- We want to go, sir.
!
Then come and tell him how you feel.
Come and tell him
how much we are suffering here.
Come! Everybody, come.
!
So, you...
you are the big man now, huh?
?
Hmm?
Where will you be going? Huh?
?
Will you surrender to the other NDF camp?
NDF
?
No. They will eat you.
And what of ECOMOD? Huh?
?
That might be better, but what next?
Jail?
?
War crimes?
Huh?
?
You think you can just go
and do what you want in peace?
?
You will go back to your village
and your family will not
associate themselves with you.
Huh? You will be nothing.
?
You and your uneducated, poor mind,
you'll be nothing.
Nobody will care for you. Huh?
Look at you.
And you will wake up and you will rise
and see the sunrise and see the sunset,
and you can just wait all day, all day,
br>
with thousands of men just like you,
waiting for somebody to give you a job.
Huh?
?
That is what you want to go and do?
You are stupid!
!
You have nothing!
No future!
!
I am your future.
You fucking die here, sir.
What?
?
How are you going to shoot me
if you don't have bullets?
?
And you, Agu?
You wanna kill Commandant?
?
Hey, Agu, I want you
to kill Commandant. Come.
,
Push it.
- Push it.
- Do it.
-
Come, Agu, come.
Put it here. Here!
!
A-ha! A-ha!
Wanna kill Commandant?
?
Do it, Agu.
Do it.
Kill Commandant!
!
You wanna surrender?
?
Huh?
You wanna surrender?
?
Yes.
Hey, Agu.
Just get out.
Just remember,
when you are all poor and hungry
you'll remember me!
!
You'll remember your Commandant.
Just go! Just go!
!
Come on. Everybody, let's move!
- Yes, sir!
- Come on, let's go.
And know that I will be
calling for you one day.
Go and drink gunpowder tea
and playing draughts.
No, no, no. You remember me.
You remember your Commandant.
You're gonna say, "Yeah!"
Remember, I will call for you again...
and you'll come.
Remember.
They will just lock you up in jail!
You are stupid!
!
When the time come back,
the other ones,
they'll come eat you.
Just chop for you...
your heart.
Agu, you stay here because they don't...
, ...
Halt! Stop there!
!
Who are you?
?
- Who are you?
- NDF, sir!
NDF !
And what is your mission here?
?
Surrender, sir!
!
Raise up your arms!
All weapons in the air!
All of you!
!
Now turn and face the bush!
Don't look at my face!
Put your weapons on the ground!
!
Step back.
Step back!
!
And turn around!
I said, turn around!
!
All right, hands up!
, !
Hands up! Sit on the floor!
!
Sit down!
Put your hands on your head!
!
Don't look at my face!
Agu, how are you settling in?
?
Hmm?
I know things are hard.
I've been there, remember?
?
We are all here to help you.
Okay?
?
I am not knowing
how long I am staying here...
but I'm staying here for a long time.
..
Some week, some month, I am not knowing.
D
All I am knowing
is how it is feeling here.
I am knowing the sound of people screaming
and the smell of dead bodies...
and I am knowing the feeling of
the brown-brown and djamba in my blood.
Hey, calm down!
!
This is your home!
No, they are giving us poison there!
!
- They want us to die!
- Yes!
- !
- They want us to die!
- Calm!
- !
Preacher is tiring of this place.
He's saying, "The war is not over,
"and they are needing fighters like us."
We need money for here.
We need money. Eh?
?
You can't stay here without money.
And we're soldiers,
fighting is what we know.
That's what we should do.
Have you forgotten?
We have food to eat.
?
- We have shelter.
- Shh!
And even we learn, we learn.
- And even we learn, we learn.
- Yeah.
You for shut up!
!
You NRC soldier,
with the talk, you talk too much.
NRC
Agu, I can't stay here. I'm leaving.
,
Preacher!
!
- Preacher!
- Let's go!
!
Randy, don't go into the bush again.
Don't follow Preacher.
Randy!
!
I don't like when you look into my eyes.
So if I look at a table,
how can I talk to you?
Amy.
She thinks that my no speaking
is because I can't be
explaining myself like baby,
but I am not like baby.
I am like old man
and she's like small girl
because I am fighting in war
and she's not even knowing what war is.
Try.
Try to talk to me about
some of your experiences...
or try to tell me what you are thinking.
I'm thinking about my future.
Very good.
So how do you see your future?
Do me this favor, okay?
?
I think if you talk to me about it,
it will make you feel better.
I saw terrible things...
and I did terrible things.
So if I'm talking to you,
it will make me sad...
and it will make you, too, sad.
In this life...
I just want to be happy in this life.
If I'm telling this to you...
you will think that...
I am some sort of beast...
or devil.
I am all of these things...
but I also having mother...
father...
brother and sister once.
They loved me.